<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Design Pattern on Coding N Concepts</title>
    <link>http://codingnconcepts.com/tags/design-pattern/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Design Pattern on Coding N Concepts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://codingnconcepts.com/tags/design-pattern/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Decorator Design Pattern Using Java</title>
      <link>http://codingnconcepts.com/java/decorator-design-pattern-using-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://codingnconcepts.com/java/decorator-design-pattern-using-java/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Decorator design pattern is used to add a new feature on the existing object by wrapping it with a decorator class.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Singleton Design Pattern Using Java</title>
      <link>http://codingnconcepts.com/java/singleton-design-pattern-using-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://codingnconcepts.com/java/singleton-design-pattern-using-java/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This problem is frequently asked in the interview to check your understanding on singleton design pattern. This program answers following artefacts of singleton design pattern:-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to make singleton class thread safe?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using double checked locking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to prevent deserialization to create new object of singleton class?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using readResolve method to return same instance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to prevent cloning to create a new object of singleton class?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;override clone method to return same instance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to prevent reflexion to create a new object of singleton class?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;check instance exist in private constructor and throw exception if already exist
You can find the singleton pattern implementation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Elevator (Lift) in Java</title>
      <link>http://codingnconcepts.com/java/elevator-implementation-using-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://codingnconcepts.com/java/elevator-implementation-using-java/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Implementation of Elevator or Lift has been asked in many interviews. I have tried to implement it using muti-threading and TreeSet. TreeSet is used to store incoming request. It is a good choice here as it removes the duplicate requests and implements NavigableSet which provide you methods such as floor and ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elevator in this program implements following features -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If elevator is going up or down, it checks for nearest floor request to process first in that direction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there is no request to process, it waits at last processed floor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a new request comes while elevator is processing a request. It process the new request first if it is nearest than the processing floor in same direction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>