<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Algorithm on Coding N Concepts</title>
    <link>http://codingnconcepts.com/tags/algorithm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Algorithm on Coding N Concepts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://codingnconcepts.com/tags/algorithm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Eggs and 100 Floors Problem</title>
      <link>http://codingnconcepts.com/puzzle/2-eggs-and-100-floors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://codingnconcepts.com/puzzle/2-eggs-and-100-floors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This problem is frequently asked in interview to evaluate candidate&amp;rsquo;s understanding on linear search and binary search. I have tried to explain this problem as easy as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a building of 100 floors. One of the floors is the highest floor (say Nth floor) an egg can be dropped from without breaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If an egg is dropped from that floor (N) or above (N+1, N+2, &amp;hellip;), it will break.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it is dropped from any floor below (N-1, N-2, &amp;hellip;), it will not break and you can drop the egg again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given two eggs, find the floor (N) an egg can be dropped from without breaking in &lt;strong&gt;minimum number of drops&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fibonacci Series</title>
      <link>http://codingnconcepts.com/java/fibonacci-series-using-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://codingnconcepts.com/java/fibonacci-series-using-java/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fibonacci series implementation in java is frequently asked question in interview at fresher level. Moreover, it is a very famous example to show how to use recursive function in java.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bubble Sort</title>
      <link>http://codingnconcepts.com/java/bubble-sort-using-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://codingnconcepts.com/java/bubble-sort-using-java/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-it-is-called-bubble-sort-&#34;&gt;Why it is called bubble sort ?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bubble Sort is nothing but a comparison algorithm where -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the end of first iteration, largest element in the array get placed at last index&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the end of second iteration, second largest element in the array get placed at second last index and so on&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This way large elements are moving towards the last indexes and hence small elements are moving towards the starting indexes which is also termed as smaller elements &amp;ldquo;bubble&amp;rdquo; to the top of the list that is why it is called bubble sort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>